Guide to the John Audley, Album
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Album containing 165 letters from various correspondents, addressed to John Audley, Chancellor of the Archdiocese of York, and to his father, Edward Audley of Huntington]
1670-1744
OSBORN C195
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 volume)
Chief topics in the letters are ecclesiastical affairs in the York diocese and affairs of Cambridge University.
Audley, John, 1680-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn c195. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
- Osborn c195
  - AISLABIE, JOHN, 1670-1742
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1736 Sep 5
      Scope and Contents
      Studley
      1 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      195/37
  - ANDREW, JOHN, D. 1747
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720 Oct 15
      Doctors Commons
      1 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      195/38
  - ANGLESEY, ARTHUR ANNESLEY, 7TH EARL OF, D. 1737
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720 Oct 19
      n.p.
      3 p.; 20 x 15 cm.
      195/39
  - ATTERBURY, FRANCIS, BP. OF ROCHESTER, 1662-1732
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), n.d.
      Bromly
      2 p.; 18 x 15 cm.
      195/40
  - B., TH.
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1725 Aug 6
      Standish
      2 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      195/51
  - BATHURST, ALLEN BATHURST, 1ST EARL, 1684-1775
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720 Oct 13
      Rainbow
      1 p.; 17 x 12 cm.
      195/41
  - BISSE, PHILIP, BP. OF HEREFORD, 1667-1721
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [no year]
      [no year], Feb 1
      195/42
  - BETTESWORTH, JOHN, 1678-1751
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [no year]
      [no year], Jan 18
      1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      195/43
  - BLACKBURNE, LANCELOT, ABP. OF YORK, 1658-1743
    - 5 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1724
      1724 [various dates]
      various places
      5 p.; various sizes
      195/44-48
  - BLAND, SIR JOHN, 5TH BART., 1691-1743
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1729 Oct 2
      Kippax Park
      195/49
  - BROWN, JOHN, ARCHDEACON OF PETERBOROUGH, D. 1764
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1718 Nov 17
      Peterborough
      2 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      195/50
  - CALAMY, BENJAMIN, 1642-1686
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1676 Jan 13
      Cambridge
      1 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      195/52
  - CARTE, SAMUEL, 1653-1740
    - ALS to Edward Audley, 1738 Jan 16
      Symonds Inn
      3 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      195/53
  - CARTE, THOMAS, 1686-1754
    - ALS to Edward Audley, 1733 May 25
      1 p.; 19 x 17 cm.
      195/54
  - CHOLMONDELY, PENELOPE (BARRY), LADY CHOLMONDELY, 1707-1786
    - ALS to [John Audley (b. 1680)], 1737 Oct 28
      Calais
      1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Women Writers
      195/55
  - [CHUTE, FRANCIS, D. 1745]
    - 3 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [no year]
      Number 56 is dated [no year] Jun 21,
      nos. 57 and 58 are not dated,
      3 p.; 21 x 18 cm.
      Letter on p. 57 contains a reference
      to Alexander Pope (1688-1744).
      195/56-58
  - CLIFTON, SIR GERVAS, 4TH BART., D. 1731
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1717 Jan 20
      1 p.; 19 x 18 cm.
      See also 195/101-102.
      195/59
  - COPLEY, ROBERT
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1732 Aug 21
      Nether Hall
      2 p.; 20 x 18 cm.
      195/60
  - COTTON, CLEMENT
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [ca. 1718]
      Payment for purchase of a Matthew
      Prior (1664-1721) publication[?].
      195/61
  - COTTON, CLEMENT
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), n.d.
      [Twickenham]
      1 p.; 20 x 18 cm.
      Refers to Stephens Hales
      (1677-1761).
      195/62
  - COTTON, JOHN [?COTTON, SIR JOHN, 4TH BART., D. 1752]
    - ALS to [Edward Audley], 1740 Jul 17
      St Neots
      1 p.; 18 x 15 cm.
      195/63
  - DAWES, SIR WILLIAM, BART., ABP. OF YORK, 1671-1724
    - 36 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1717-1724
      43 p.; various sizes
      195/ 1-36
  - EDEN, SIR JOHN, 2ND BART., D.1728
    - 4 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720-29
      4 p.; various sizes
      References to Thomas Tickell
      (1686-1740) and to Charles Spencer,
      3rd earl of Sunderland (1674-1722).
      195/64-67
  - FRANKLAND, SIR THOMAS, 3RD BART., CA. 1685-1747
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1737 Nov 16
      Sunbury
      195/68
  - FOULIS, HENRY
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1725 Jun 15
      Edinburgh
      See also 195/72.
      195/69
  - GOOCH, SIR THOMAS, 2ND BART., BP. OF ELY, 1674-1734
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720 Sep 27
      Caius College
      3 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      195/70
  - [GOODRICKE, SIR JOHN, 5TH BART., 1708-1789]
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1734 Apr 19
      1 p.; 21 x 19 cm.
      195/71
  - GRAHAM, REGINALD, BART, D. 1735
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1725 Jun 2
      Norton Conyers
      1 p.; 21 x 17 cm.
      See also 195/69.
      195/72
  - GREEN, THOMAS, BP. OF ELY, 1658-1738
    - 6 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1729-1734
      Ely House
      6 p.; various sizes
      Letter 195/76 refers to articles
      against Richard Bentley (1662-1742).
      195/73-78
  - HALE, SIR BERNARD, 1677-1729
    - 5 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1718-1725
    - Kingswalden and London 8 p.; various sizes 195/79-83
  - HAMILTON, J.
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1733 Apr 13
      Myton
      2 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      195/84
  - HARBORD, H. [?HARBORD, GUNTON NORFOLK, D. 1742]
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1730 Jun 20
      Bath
      1 p.; 20 x 17 cm.
      195/85
  - HATHERGILL, MARMADUKE
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1722
      1722 [no month] 13
      Westminster
      195/86
  - HAYTER, THOMAS, BP. OF LONDON, 1702-1762
    - 7 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1725-36
      London
      8 p.; various sizes
      195/87-93
  - HERRING, THOMAS, ABP. OF CANTERBURY, 1693-1757
    - 3 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1743-44
      195/94-96
  - HOOPER, GEORGE, BP. OF BATH AND WELLS, 1640-1727
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1716 Feb 10
      Kensington
      1 p.; 20 x 15 cm.
      195/97
  - FOX, GEORGE (OF BRAMHAM PARK, YORKS.)
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1737 Aug 28
      Bramham Park
      1 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
      195/98
  - JESSOP, WILLIAM (OF ESSEX HOUSE)
    - 2 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1719
    - 1719 Jan 30 and Feb 7 Essex House London 5 p.; 31 x 20 cm. 195/99-100
  - KINNOUL, GEORGE HAY, 7TH EARL OF, D. 1758
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1718-20
      1718 Jan 20 and 1720 Mar 8
      Brodsworth and Whitehall
      2 p.; various sizes
      195/101-102
  - KENNETT, WHITE, BP. OF PETERBOROUGH, 1660-1723
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1709 Sep 16
    - [Peterborough] 1 p.; 14 x 16 cm. 195/103
  - LAMPLUGH, THOMAS, B. 1687
    - 7 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680) [and his brother], 1716-1737
      9 p.; various sizes
      195/104-110
  - LAYE, A.
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720 Nov 29
      2 p.; 20 x 15 cm.
      See also 195/152.
      195/111
  - LEVINZ, MRS. A.
    - 3 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), various
      various dates
      Grove
      6 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      See 195/115-125 from William Levinz.
      195/112-114
  - LEVINZ, WILLIAM
    - 11 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1719-1738
      Grove and London
      16 p.; various sizes
      See 195/112-114 from Mrs. Levinz.
      195/115-125
  - LEXINGTON, ROBERT SUTTON, 2ND BARON, 1661-1723
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1717] Apr 8
    - Kelham 2 p.; 18 x 15 cm. 195/126
  - LLOYD, WILLIAM, BP. OF WORCESTER, 1627-1717
    - ALS to [John Audley (b. 1680)], 1704 Jan 15
      [Worcester]
      2 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      Notes on visions of Revelations.
      195/127
  - MIDDLETON, CONYERS, 1683-1750
    - 4 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1718-34
      195/128-131
  - MILNER, SIR WILLIAM, 1ST BART., D. 1745
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1732 Aug 16]
      Hutton
      Announcing the death of Sir D'arcy
      Dawes, his brother-in-law, son of
      the Abp. of York.
      195/132
  - ORMONDE, MARY (SOMERSET) BUTLER, DUCHESS OF, 1665-1733
    - 2 ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1715 Jan
      4 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      195/133-133A
  - PARKER, BENJAMIN, D. 1747
    - 2 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1739
      Inner Temple
      2 p.; 21 x 18 cm.
      195/134-135
  - PASKE, THOMAS, D. 1720
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1717 Jan 14
      Doctor's Commons
      1 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      Refers to Sir Nathaniel Lloyd
      (1669-1745).
      195/136
  - POCKLINGTON, J.
    - ALS to Edward Audley, 1695 Apr 27
      2 p.; 21 x 15 cm.
      195/137
  - PRIOR, MATTHEW, 1644-1721
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1720 Oct 13
      Wimpole
      2 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      One of a series Audley sent out
      campaigning for election to
      parliament as member from Cambridge
      University; there were many
      tentative candidates, including
      Prior, who withdrew Oct. 15; see
      also Osborn Shelves c 195 numbers:
      39, 38, 64-67, 70, 111, 125,
      151, 171.
    - 195/138
  - SANDWICH, EDWARD MONTAGU, 3RD EARL OF, 1670-1729
    - 2 ALS to [John Audley], n.d.
      2 p.; 21 x 18 cm. and 16 x 18 cm.
      195/139-140
  - SEYMOUR, ELIZABETH, VICOUNTESS HINCHINGBROOKE, D. 1671
    - 4 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1725
      7 p.; various sizes
      Letter 195/143 makes reference to
      Sir Clement Cotterell (d. 1758).
      195/141-144
  - REYNOLDS, RICHARD, BP. OF LINCOLN, 1674-1743
    - 2 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1735
      1735 Dec 22 and Jan 16
      195/145-146
  - SHARP, THOMAS, ARCHDEACON, 1693-1758
    - 2 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1736-39
      1736 Sept 4 and 1739 Aug 23
      Durham
      2 p.; 21 x 17 cm.
      195/147-148
  - SHERLOCK, THOMAS, BP. OF LONDON, 1679-1761
    - 2 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1740
      1740 Jun 24 and Jul 1
      3 p.; various sizes
      195/149-150
  - SNAPE, ANDREW, PROVOST, KINGS COLLEGE, CAMBRIDGE, 1675-1742
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1720]
      [Cambridge]
      Refers to Matthew Prior (1664-1721).
      195/151
  - STAPYLTON, M.
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1720] Jan 27
      2 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      See also Osborn Shelves c 195/111
      195/152
  - STILLINGFLEET, EDWARD, BP. OF WORCESTER, 1635-1699
    - 4 ALS to [Edward Audley], 1685-1686
      [London]
      4 p.; 22 x 17 cm.
      195/153-156
  - TEMPEST, S.
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1724 Aug 12
      Brough
      195/157
  - TREVOR, RICHARD, BP. OF DURHAM, 1707-1771
    - 4 ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1737-1738]
      London and Oxford
      5 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
      195/158-161
  - WILSON, THOMAS, BP. OF SODOR AND MAN, 1663-1755
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1737 Nov 2
      Isle of Man
      195/162
  - WATERLAND, DANIEL, 1683-1740
    - 2 ALS to an unnamed recipient, [1723]
      195/163-164
  - WAUGH, JOHN, BP. OF CARLISLE, 1661-1734
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1728 Mar 29
      Queen's Square
      1 p.; 22 x 17 cm.
      195/165
  - WIDDRINGTON, WILLIAM WIDDRINGTON, 4TH BARON, 1678-1743
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1731] Jan 6
      Ct. Rider Street, St. James's
      Refers to the Robinson case,
      see 195/105.
      195/166
  - WILKINS, JOHN, BP. OF CHESTER, 1614-1672
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient
      1 p.; 21 x 18 cm.
      195/167
  - NOTTINGHAM AND WINCHILSEA, DANIEL FINCH, EARL OF, 1689-1769
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), 1727 Jul 18
      195/168
  - WINDSOR, D., WILLOUGHBY THO.
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [1727]
      195/169
  - WINDSOR, DIXIE, 1674-1745
    - ALS to John Audley (b. 1680), [no year]
      [no year] Apr 24
      Trinity College Cambridge
      195/170
  - FENWICK, NICHO.
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1720 [Apr 4]
      [Newcastle]
      Mentions Richard Bentley,
      (1662-1742).
      195/171
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - Unidentified letter, 1739 Dec 21
      (Cf. Hinchingbrooke letters - 141f)
      195/172
  - VERNON, G.H.
    - ALS to Neville Grenville, 1872
      3 p.; 15 x 10 cm.
      The Audley letters were owned by
      Grenville.
    - 195/173